FARUQ ABDUL HAKIM

Software Developer

Address: Jember, East Java, Indonesia | Phone Number: +62 877-5087-4602

Email: faruqabdulhakim2001@gmail.com | Personal Website: https://www.faruqabdulhakim.dev

Summary

A passionate software developer with 1-2 years of experience in **Frontend Web Development**, **Backend Development** and **Android Development**. Received Bachelor of Computer Science degree from the University of Jember in 2024. Proficient in top-notch web technologies like JavaScript, TypeScript, React.js, and Next.js, as well as backend frameworks such as Express.js and Nest.js. Also familiar with Kotlin and Jetpack Compose for Android development. I am always eager to explore new things.

Experiences

Frontend Developer

March 2024 - Present, PT. Andalan Solusi Cemerlang

- Develop several type-safe React.js applications with Typescript.
- Quality assurance of mobile application development.
- Transformed the frontend team's Git branching strategy by implementing best practices.

Freelance Developer

November 2022 - Present, Upwork

Assist clients in fulfilling their requirements. Most projects involved HTML email newsletters/signatures,
 Python automation, and frontend website development.

Mobile Development Cohort

February 2023 - July 2023, Bangkit Academy led by Google, Tokopedia, Gojek, & Traveloka

Participated in the Mobile Development cohort, focusing on learning Android native development. By the
end of the program, I joined the Android Development team to build an internal application for Nusantara
Beta Studio, streamlining their Human Resources business processes.

Programming Laboratory Assistant

July 2021 - June 2023, the University of Jember

- Engaged in various activities, including assisting lecturers in delivering classes to students and collaborating on several software development projects with the team.
- Built an organization profile website and an online webinar event registration website.

Education

University of Jember

2020 - 2024

Bachelor of Computer Science (GPA: 3.82)

Skills

- **Technical Skills:** Frontend Web Development, Backend Development, and Android Native Development.
- Software Skills: Visual Studio Code, Android Studio, Git/GitHub/GitLab, Figma, and so on.
- Soft Skills: Problem Solving, Communication & Collaboration, Project Management, and Time Management.